

Joaquin Dominguez **Data Scientist**

- New Haven, CT
- joaquin.dominguez@pm.me
- (970) 710-1235

SOCIAL

- in @joaquin-dominguez1992
- @j-dominguez9
- @joaquinmsds

PROFILE

Versatile individual with experience collecting, transforming, and organizing data for analysis to help make informed decisions. Excellent understanding and proficiency of platforms for effective data analyses, including SQL, spreadsheets, Tableau, R, and D3. Strong communication, organizational, and analytical skills.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Data Science

Southern Methodist University

2021 - 2023

Master of Arts, Government **Extension Studies**

Harvard University

2018 - 2020

Bachelor of Science, Psychology

Colorado State University

2011 - 2015

SKILLS

- D3
- Python

CSS

EXPERIENCE

Financial Advisor

August 2020 - August 2021 | Northwestern Mutual, New Haven, CT

- · Assisted individuals and businesses in meeting their financial goals by employing a comprehensive financial planning process.
- · Specialized in investment risk management, debt management, insurance, and retirement planning.

Program Administrator

January 2018 - June 2018 | African Studies Center, Boston University

- · Coordinated university academic and social events
- · Consolidated and drafted federal grant compliance reports
- · Developed analytic reports to showcase Center activities and achievements as part of the 2018-2022 Title VI Federal Grant Application

Stakeholder Services Specialist

August 2017 - December 2017 | CFP Board, Washington, D.C.

- Maintained correspondence with 90+ stakeholders daily
- · Optimized financial planner certification process

Paralegal/Office Manager

January 2017 - July 2017 | Law Office of Thomas W. Martin, Fort Collins, CO

- · Drafted and filed client documentation to court
- Maintained correspondence with new and existing clients
- · Managed all files and scheduling for office

CERTIFICATES

Google Data Analytics - 2021

Rigorous hands-on program that covers the entire scope of the data analysis process

REFERENCES

Professor

Dr. Bivin Sadler

Statistics, Data Science Southern Methodist University Email: bsadler@mail.smu.edu

Professor

Dr. Sasha Sparsha

Thesis Advisor, Government Harvard University Email: saha@fas.harvard.edu

LANGUAGES

- English
 - Spanish
- French

INTERESTS

• SQL • Java

Music Reading Traveling Cooking

•3 **■** •7 **■**

JavaScript